In this house... if you've seen one ghost... you haven't seen them all.
Beetlejuice is a fantasy, comedy film directed by Tim Burton.
A newly dead New England couple seeks help from a deranged demon exorcist
to scare an affluent New York family out of their home.
Adam, played by Alec Baldwin.
Barbara, played by Geena Davis.
Lydia, played by Winona Ryder.
Delia, played by Catherine O'Hara.
Charles, played by Jeffrey Jones.
Betelgeuse, played by Michael Keaton.
Beetlejuice is a 1988 American gothic horror comedy film directed by Tim Burton from a screenplay by
Michael McDowell and Warren Skaaren based on a story by McDowell and Larry Wilson.
The film stars Michael Keaton as Betelgeuse, along with Alec Baldwin, Geena
Davis, Jeffrey Jones, Catherine O'Hara and Winona Ryder.
The plot revolves around Adam and Barbara Maitland, a recently deceased couple.
As ghosts, they are not allowed to leave their house.
They contact Betelgeuse, a sleazy "bio-exorcist", to
scare the house's new inhabitants away.
The film prominently features music from Harry
Belafonte's albums Calypso and Jump Up Calypso.
Beetlejuice was released in the United States on March 30, 1988, by Warner Bros.
The film was a critical and commercial success, grossing
$84 million against a $15 million budget.
It won the Academy Award for Best Makeup and three Saturn Awards: Best Horror
Film, Best Makeup, and Best Supporting Actress for Sylvia Sidney.
The film's success spawned a media franchise, consisting of an animated television series,
video games, a 2018 stage musical, and a 2024 sequel, Beetlejuice Beetlejuice.
The film explores themes of skeleton, afterlife, calypso, supernatural, arts.
The tone is lighthearted and mind_bending.